hi and welcome back to this really quick
remake of mango ice cream I made it the
other week wasn't happy with the result
it was mainly just a flavor and a color
but we're going to remake it again with
totally different numbers and see if it
turns out any different so let's get a
move on nice and quickly so for this
version of mango gelato we're dropping
the fat right way down to 6% so you're
going to need 400 G of mango flesh I'm
just using the sliced mangoes here 215 G
milk 170 G of cream I use 33% whipping
cream 80 g of sugar 71 G of dextrose 65
G of skim milk powder and 4 G of my
stabilizer
blend so it's nice and easy one to make
in here we've got our milk and our cream
just gently heating up and what we're
going to do is combine all our dry
ingredients together like this we have
our sugar and our dextrose our milk
powder and our stabilizer blend here
here what we're going to do is just stir
it all
together we you do this lump there let's
get rid of
that you stir your stabilizer in to make
sure that it's really finely combined
with the other powders if you don't do
that then when you put your stabilizer
into your liquid it will Clump up and
not do anything so that is why we do
it so fill that in there we are
literally just going to pour all of that
into there and get a larger whisk and
mix it up now the stabilizer I'm using
here needs 80 to 85° Centigrade so
that's what we're going to go up to and
we will come back once I'm there off the
heat we're just going to continue to
stir it for about 5 minutes we're just
going to make sure that stabilizer is
completely
hydrated this is a really good one so I
don't really have any issues using this
at all if you're interested in what
stabilizer I use for my home ice cream
it is special ingredients I will put a
link below I'm not affiliated with them
I just find their stabilizer possibly
one of the best out there for home ice
cream makers so the next stage here is
our mangoes so they've been set in here
there's actually quite a lot of water
come out there so I'm just going to
remove that and we are going to drop our
mango straight into our blender and pop
the lid
on and we're just going to process this
on low for a few
minutes and after that's
done we are going to add in
our Dairy
base straight in like
so
lid back
on and process it
again and after that's done we are just
going to take it off here and put it in
a
container so I actually decided to
strain this one cuz it's a really
viscous
base so just got a another clean bowl
and pour it through a fine mesh Sie it
actually all went through quite nicely
no lumps at all well no large lumps I
should say and when I'm stirring it in
this bowl it's just slightly too viscous
so it's slightly too thick so what I do
is I take the cream out again this is
just standard whipping cream and just
added 50 to 75 milliliters of cream back
in there just to loosen it back up a
little bit and then it was perfect to
put into our machine as you can see here
as I'm pouring it in is quite thick for
an ice cream base but it will churn
really really nicely as you can see
here at this stage we're going to load
it in our container get it in a freezer
and see how this one turned
out mango part two um been in the
freezer a few days down the
line let's get some scooped up compare
this to the first mango one we did last
week so first thing to note color much
better
just what I wanted I wanted that orangey
yellow color obviously it's it's orange
flesh but by the time you add all the
dairy and everything else it brings the
orange color down we've got a nice
yellowy color to
it smells like it should
do much better something to
note what really
good this is gel quite low
fat but also because of the amount of
fiber that you get from the inclusion of
quite a lot of mango flesh you get a
really good overrun so what you get is
this slightly whipped texture to it it's
incredibly light flavor lingers really
really nicely so you're actually going
to get a good amount of ice cream out of
your base if you do this one this is
much better this is exactly what I
wanted I wanted something a bit more a
bit lighter a bit more refresh freshing
with a stronger color stronger smell
stronger flavor everything about this is
where I wanted to be in that first one
so thanks very much for watching mango
ice cream or gelato number
two I'll see you next
[Music]
week